you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
《ナルト : カエル… オレはカエル…》
Frog... I'm a frog...
♬(ガマ吉)「かえるのうたが」
I can hear... the frog song.
Connecting Hearts
《ガマ竜の心…》
Gamatatsu's... mind...
♬(ガマ竜)「かえるのうたが」
I can hear... the frog song.
《相手の心を読み… 応える》
Read his mind...
and respond to it...
♪♪「きこえてくるよ」
♪♪「かえるのうたが」
- I can hear...
- the frog song.
♪♪「チンチロ チンチロ チンチロリン」
♪♪「きこえてくるよ」
- Chinchiro chinchiro chinchirorin.
- I can hear...
♪♪「チンチロ チンチロ チンチロリン」
♬(ガマ吉)「かえるのうたが」
Chinchiro chinchiro...
- ...chinchirorin.
- I can hear...
♬(ガマ竜)「かえるのうたが」
♪♪「きこえてくるよ」
- ...the frog song.
- I can hear... the frog song.
♪♪「チンチロ チンチロ チンチロリン」
♪♪「かえるのうたが」
- Chinchiro chinchiro chinchirorin.
- I can hear... the frog song.
(ガマ吉)ナルト！ まだまだ
心を開いとらんようじゃのぉ。
Naruto, you don't look like you've
opened up your mind yet!
ガマ竜の動きに踊らされとる！
Don't get swept up by
Gamatatsu's movements!
ガマ竜から心のバイブスを感じ それを
お前流に表現すればいいんじゃ。
Communicate with Gamatatsu's mind,
arrange things your way,
then just express yourself!
あぁ！
Yeah!
あっ!?
Huh?
あ… ハハハハ。
わ… わりぃ。
Sorry...
♪♪「ほら ガマ吉が ないている
ゲロゲロ ゲロゲロ ゲーロゲロ」
- Look Gamakichi is singing.
- Gero gero gero gero gero...
♪♪「ほら ガマ竜も なきだした」
- Look Gamatatsu is singing too.
♪♪「ケロケロ ケロケロ ケーロケロ」
- Kero kero kero kero kero...
《ガマ竜の… 心…》
Gamatatsu's... mind...
あっ あの雲…➡
Ah, that cloud...
looks like a cream puff...
シュークリームみたい。 おいしそう！
It looks yummy!
《やっと心が通い合ったかのぉ》
They've finally reached
each other's mind...
あれ？ 今なんか
ピーンとこなかった？ なぁ ガマ竜！
Oh? Did you feel something
just now, Gamatatsu?
(ガマ竜)そんなの ボクに言われても
わからないよ。
Why are you asking me this?
(自来也)フフフフ…。
あっ チョウチョウ！
え？
A butterfly!
(２人)ジャンケン ポン！
What?!
- Rock, paper, scissors, go!
あいこでしょ！ あいこでしょ！
あいこでしょ…！
- Rock, paper, scissors, go!
- Go!
- Go! Go! Go!
お前の名前は？
(２人)ガマ竜！
- What's your name?
- Gamatatsu!
それは
気が合ったとは言わんじゃろ。
This doesn't mean
you're on the same wavelength.
♬(２人)「かえるのうたが」
- I can hear... the frog song.
♪♪「きこえてくるよ」
♪♪「チンチロ チンチロ チンチロリン」
- Chinchiro chinchiro chinchirorin
あ… もう 動けねえ…。
I can't move anymore...
ほれ… これでも食わんか。
Here!
Eat it!
Thanks.
結局 皆 お前を➡
I think we all have to
acknowledge you.
認めざるをえないのかもしれんな。
ん？
What?
(自来也)ガマ竜もガマ吉も➡
Gamatatsu, Gamakichi,
Sakura, Tsunade... and myself...
サクラや綱手 そして わしも➡
いつの間にか
お前の がんばりを認めてきた。
We all admit you've worked
really hard.
何が そうさせるのか。
I wonder what's pushing you forward.
そりゃ あきらめねえ➡
Well, I never give up and I have guts.
ド根性だってばよ。
サスケは…。
Sasuke...
Hmm?
サスケは どうかな…。
I wonder if Sasuke will...
オレを認めてくれてるのかな。
acknowledge that about me...?
だと いいがな…。
I hope he does...
ん？
なに…。
What...?
《コイツに 暁のことを
話すわけにはいかないのう》
I can't tell him about the Akatsuki...
(自来也)おい お前たち。
Hey, all of you!
わしは ここを
離れなければならなくなった。
I have something to do,
so I must leave.
すまんが 里に帰って
残りの修業を➡
Can you go back to the village
お前さんたちで ナルトに
つけてやってくれんかのう。
and help with the rest
of Naruto's training?
おう 任せておけ！
おやつをくれたら いいよ。
We'll take care of it!
I'll do it if you give me
some snacks.
わかった わかった。 頼むぞ。
All right, all right.
I'm counting on you!
《ナルト がんばれよ。
Good luck, Naruto!
がんばって 本当に 火影に…》
Work hard and truly become...
the Hokage...
《あきらめねえ ド根性で
がんばれのう ナルト…》
Naruto, good luck with
your never-say-die spirit...
(綱手)新手の敵？
A new enemy?
(パックン)そうらしい。 強敵のようだ。
相当 慌てていたからな。
Right. The enemy seems
really hard to beat.
I saw that the team
was really flustered.
(綱手)それで これを 私に…。
Therefore, you're giving this to me?
(シズネ)結晶の中に
何か入ってますね。
There's something inside the crystal.
(パックン)敵の術に やられた
シノの寄壊蟲じゃ。
It's Shino's Parasitic Insect that was
overcome by the enemy's Jutsu.
カカシが 大至急
分析してくれとのことだ。
Kakashi requested an
analysis right away.
《綱手 : これは まさか…。
This can't be...
ウワサには聞いたことはあるが…》
I've only heard about it
through rumors...
シズネ！ これを分析班に！
Shizune, take this to the forensics team.
大至急だ！
はい！
It's urgent!
なに!? エロ仙人が どっか消えた？
All right!
What?! The Pervy Sage disappeared?!
それで これを渡してくれと➡
Yeah, he asked me
to give this to you.
頼まれた。
貸せ！
Give it to me!
"Please take care of snacks for Gamatatsu"
さっさと里に帰るぞ 支度せえ！
ガク…。
We're going back to our village.
Pack up!
(カブト)ん？ どうした？
What's wrong?
(幽鬼丸)
見て 今までボクたちのいた谷が➡
Look...
I can see the valley
where we stayed until now.
ずっと見えるよ。
大蛇丸様が 待っているんだ➡
Orochimaru-sama is waiting.
Let's go.
行くよ。
あっ は はい。
Oh, okay!
(キバ)どうだ？ 赤丸。
Do you smell something, Akamaru?
(カカシ)何か見つかったか？ キバ。
Did you find anything, Kiba?
(キバ)ダメだ 今んところ
なんも臭いはねえ。
No, we haven't picked up
any scents.
(ヒナタ)白眼でも 何も見えません。
I used Byakugan,
but couldn't see anything.
あっ。
Oh!
《ヒナタ : コウモリ…》
A bat?
(シノ)気配はある。
There are some signs.
Huh? Where?!
(キバ)どこだ!?
(シノ)オレの蟲のことだ。
I'm talking about my insects.
So don't get so excited.
そんなに緊張することはない。
なんだ 蟲の話か 脅かすなよ。
Your insects?
Don't get me excited like that.
そりゃ お前の蟲は
何万といるんだから➡
Well, you had tens of thousands
of insects,
１匹くらい生き残ってても
不思議じゃねえだろ。
so I wouldn't be surprised
if one of them is still alive.
(シノ)だが その 数万分の１匹が
新しい敵と遭遇したときには➡
But that one insect
out of tens of thousands
that managed to survive
becomes an asset to us..
貴重な存在となる。
(キバ)貴重な存在？
An asset to us?
(シノ)なぜなら その蟲は
敵の術を受けて➡
Because it has survived despite
incurring the enemy's Jutsu.
生き延びているからだ。
(カカシ)その蟲は 敵の術に
免疫を持ったということか。
You mean the insects are
now immune to the enemy's Jutsu...
オレの蟲たちの一生は
短いもので わずか数時間。
My insects' life span is only
a few hours at most.
短期間で その免疫を持った蟲を
増やすことが出来る。
And the immune insect can breed
in a very short period.
そりゃ すげえじゃねえかよ！
That's amazing!
(シノ)あくまで 可能性だ。
But it's just a possibility.
I'm not sure if it'll be successful.
上手くいくかは わからない。
とにかく 生き残った蟲を
探さなければ。
Anyway, I must find as many
surviving insects as possible.
私たちも手伝うよ。
おう 任せとけ！
We'll help you.
Yeah! Count on us!
(シノ)断わる。
なんだと!?
There's no need.
What?!
(シノ)なぜなら 蟲の探知は
オレにしかできない。
Only I can search for
the insects.
お前たちにウロウロされて➡
I can't have you stepping on them
while you're searching around blindly.
せっかくの蟲を
踏み潰されたのでは➡
シャレにならない。
もっと やんわりした断わり方
できねえのかよ。
Can't you refuse our help
with a little more finesse?
(シノ)事実をぼかした言い方は
時間のムダだ。
I don't want to waste time
by being vague.
(カカシ)まっ いいだろう。
That's fine.
シノは 生き残った蟲を探せ。
Shino, you go find the insects
that survived.
オレたちは 引き続き
探索を続ける。
And we'll continue our search.
よし 行くぞ 赤丸。
(赤丸)ワン！
All right, let's go, Akamaru!
(リンジ)ヘヘッ 悪いな ピンゾロのアラシだ。
Sorry, but I've had a series
of snake eyes.
(キギリ)アニキ イカサマしてんじゃ
ねえでしょうね？
Aniki, I hope you're not cheating.
(リンジ)フン まさか。
(リンジ)オレとお前らとじゃ
持って生まれた運が違うのよ。
No way!
I was born lucky,
and I'm totally different from you.
ヘヘ そりゃ こっちが負けるわけだ。
No wonder I'm losing.
(キギリ)じゃあ その運が
サイコロに残ってるうちに➡
Since your luck is so strong,
オレが次 振らせてもらうぜ。
(ゴズ)遅い。
let me roll the dice
that you just used!
She's late.
(キホウ)ああ 惜しい！
もうひと転がりしてくれりゃぁ。
Shoot! Almost!
Just one more roll!
(リンジ)オメエもやるかい？
いい暇つぶしになるぜ。
Wanna try?
It's a good way to kill time.
チッ 無視かよ。 まあいいや。
You're ignoring me?
だが オレには意外だったぜ。
Fine.
(リンジ)オメエさんが 紅蓮さんの帰りを
じっと待っているとはな。
Fine. But I'm a little surprised...
That you're waiting for Guren
to come back.
(リンジ)どちらかというと
反抗的だったからよ。
You seemed defiant to me,
この機に逃げ出すと思ってたぜ。
so I thought you'd take advantage
of this chance to escape.
逃げても 彼女には勝てない。
Even if I could escape,
I couldn't beat her.
ほお こりゃまた意外な答えだ。
That's a surprising answer.
オメエが紅蓮さんに
従うつもりでいたとは。
I didn't know you had decided
to obey Guren-san.
お前たちこそ どうなんだ？
(リンジ)オレたち？
How about you guys?
(ゴズ)
お前たちは最初から知っていた。
Us?
You knew from the beginning...
あのアジトで生き残りを懸けた
戦いが起きることを。
that a fight for survival
would occur in that hideout.
オレには 最初から
手を組んでいるように見えたがな。
I thought you had already
joined forces with them.
ハハッ 鋭いね。 そのとおりだ。
だが 別に不思議なことじゃねえ。
You're sharp! That's right!
物騒なところじゃ
仲間がいたほうが安全だろ。
But it's not surprising.
It's better to have people who help
each other in dangerous situations.
いざというときに
手を組もうって約束してたのさ。
So when times get desperate,
we promise to help each other.
(リンジ)自分の力におごって
なにも考えねえヤツは➡
Those who overestimated
their own abilities
あそこで 次々とくたばった。
and acted thoughtlessly have died.
まあ オレたちは知恵で
生き残ったってわけだ。
So I say, our wisdom has
helped us to survive.
もっとも バトルロイヤルが途中で
止められなかったら➡
Though, at the rate we were going
in that battle royal,
オレたちだって 仲間同士で
やり合うことになったろうがな。
we might've fought each other.
(リンジ)確かに あのとき オメエさんは
１人でも 十分強かった。
It's true that you were really strong
out there all by yourself.
(リンジ)
オレたちがバラバラに戦ってるうちは➡
While we were fighting individually,
we had to keep away from you...
アンタを
わざわざ敬遠するくらいにな。
だが オレたちは４人だ。
力を合わせれば
オメエにだって負けねえ。
But we are four here.
We won't be beaten
if we stay together, not even by you.
今は
同じ紅蓮さんに仕える者同士➡
Now we all work for Guren-san...
人付き合いは
大切にしたほうがいいぜ。
You'd better socialize with the others.
(キギリ)あ～あ もうちょっとマシな
隠れ家はなかったのかねぇ。
Man, why couldn't they find
a better hideout?
(キギリ)紅蓮さんも人が悪いや。
(キギリ)こんなボロ家に
オレたち置いてけぼりとは。
Guren-san isn't nice to us.
She left us in this old shack.
あ～あ。
(キギリ)見回りに行ってくる。
I'm going on patrol.
何か わかったか？
Did you find something?
どうした？ 赤丸！
What's wrong, Akamaru?!
この情報を急いで届けてくれ。
Deliver this information quickly.
見回りに
行くんじゃなかったのか？
I thought you were out
on patrol.
ちょっと考えごとがあってな。
I had something to think about.
I'm just setting out.
今 行こうとしてたところだ。
オレもついて行こう…。
I'll go with you.
それは… さっきのオレの助言を
受け入れたってことかな？
Does that mean...
you're heeding my advice?
(カカシ)犬笛？
(キバ)あぁ。
赤丸が確かに聞こえた
って言ってる。
A dog whistle?
Right. Akamaru said
he definitely heard it.
それじゃ
相手にも犬がいるってこと？
Do you think the enemy
has a dog?
それは どうかな？
犬のにおいを完全に消すことは➡
I doubt it,
because it's more difficult to remove
dog odors than human odors.
人間より はるかに難しいからな。
犬なら オレも赤丸も
とっくに嗅ぎつけているはずだ。
And if they have a dog,
Akamaru and I would've
caught its scent long ago.
それじゃ… どうして犬笛を？
Then... why the dog whistle?
わからねえ…。
方角はわかるか？
I don't know.
いいや… だが➡
Do you know which direction
it came from?
そう遠くないところにいるのは
間違いねえだろ。
No, but I'm sure they're not far away.
やっと着いたぁ…。
We've finally arrived...
まずは 一楽のラーメンで
疲れを吹き飛ばして➡
First of all, I'm going to have ramen
at Ichiraku to refresh myself!
すぐに修業を再開だってばよ。
Then let's resume my training!
(木ノ葉丸)ナルトにいちゃん！
Naruto nii-chan!
新しい修業って 温泉で
よからぬ術をあみ出したとみた！
Huh?
I guess you created a naughty technique
at the hot springs during training, right?
ならば お色気の術 ニューバージョン！
So, I'll do the new version
of Sexy Jutsu!
わっ コラッ 木ノ葉丸！
Whoa! Hey, Konohamaru!
(木ノ葉丸)イテーッ！
Ouch!
(木ノ葉丸)思いっきり
殴ったお詫びが➡
一楽のラーメン １杯か？
So buying me one bowl
of ramen is your way of apologizing
お前が時と場所を考えずに
あの術を使ったからだろ！
for hitting me that hard?
It's because you used
that technique thoughtlessly,
without caring about the time or place!
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
おぉ これがナルトにいちゃんの
口寄せかコレ！
Oh! This is Naruto nii-chan's Summoning!
まぁ ホントは もっとデカいヤツを
呼べるけどよ➡
I can call for bigger guys,
but these brats are enough for today.
今日は コイツらで十分だってばよ。
わっ！
コイツらじゃと？
オヤジの子分って立場
忘れとるんか？
You called us brats?
Have you forgotten you're
our dad's henchman?
まぁまぁ 今日は後輩の前だから
いい格好させてくれよ。
Come on, please let me play cool
in front of him today.
それじゃ 修業の続き 始めるぜ。
Then let's start training again!
兄ちゃん 今日のおやつ
何かな～？
Brother, I wonder what
today's snack is.
楽しみだな～。
Uh-oh...
I'm looking forward to it.
《チッ… そうだった。
おやつのこと
すっかり忘れてたってばよ》
That's right. I completely forgot
about the snacks.
まぁ おやつは その…
修業のあとで ゆっくり… とな。
Well, we'll have snacks
after our training.
え～！ 今日 おやつないの？
What?! You don't have
any snacks for us?
兄ちゃん ボク帰る。
Nii-chan, I'm going home.
あぁ～ わかった わかった！
おやつ おやつ！
Okay, okay! Snack! Snack!
木ノ葉丸 これで 何かおやつ
買ってきてくれねえか？
Konohamaru,
can you buy some snacks?
(木ノ葉丸)わかったぞ コレ。
(ガマ竜)わ～い！ おやつ おやつ。
Got it!
Yahoo! Snack! Snack!
これじゃ お金が いくらあっても
足りねえってばよ。
I'll never have any money
if I keep doing this.
ん!? お前 もう全部 食ったのか！
Oh?!
Did you finish all
your snacks already?
ぐえっ…。
お～！ 器用だな コレ！
気持わりぃ…。
Oh! He's very skillful!
よし ガマ竜！ ビシッと修業に
つきあってくれれば➡
How disgusting!
Listen, Gamatatsu!
エロ仙人が 食いきれないほど
おやつを くれるそうだから➡
If you help me train really well,
Pervy Sage will give you more snacks
than you can possibly eat.
気合いを入れて やるぞ！
わ～い！ …で？
So let's work hard!
Yahoo!
こないだは タイミングを
取るところまでやったから➡
So?
Last time, we worked on how
to find the right timing.
今日は そのあとを やるってばよ。
そのあとって？
So today,
let's start where we left off.
お前が 水を吐き出したところに➡
What's that?
タイミングを合わせ
オレが チャクラを流し込む。
When you spit out the water,
I find the right timing,
and I pour in my Chakra!
((自来也 : はぁ!!))
There!
オレが タイミングを合わせるから➡
お前は 水鉄砲を撃つだけで
いいってばよ。
I'll find the perfect timing,
so you just shoot your water pistol.
水鉄砲… 水鉄砲って 何？
Water pistol...
What's a water pistol?
そりゃ 口から水遁の術で
ピュ～ッと水を吐き出してだな…。
Blast water out from your mouth
using Water Style Jutsu...
水遁？
え？
Water Style?
兄ちゃん
ボク そんなこと できないよ～。
What?!
Brother, I can't do
that kind of thing.
なに言ってんだよ！
カエルなんだから水遁くらい…。
What are you talking about?!
いや たしかに コイツは
水遁の術はできん。
You're a frog, so it's easy
for you to do Water Style.
He's right.
He can't do Water Style Jutsu.
ウソだろ!? じゃ 何のために
ここまで修業してきたんだよ！
You must be kidding!
Why have we trained together
up until now?!
そんな どなったって
できんもんは できんのじゃ!!
Even if you yell at him,
なら ガマ吉 お前がやれよ。
he can't do
something he doesn't know!
Then, Gamakichi, you do it.
なんだよ！ それくらい
協力してくれたって いいだろ！
Why? Can't you help us out?
ダメじゃ…。
N-No, I can't...
なんでだよ!!
Why not?
え!?
ちょっと…。
Come here for a bit.
なんだってばよ…。
- What...?
- Come here.
What did you say?
え？ 何？
Say what?
だから…。
はぁ？ 聞こえねえってばよ。
Because...
Huh? I can't hear you.
水遁… だからだ…。
Because it's Water Style Jutsu...
じれったいから
はっきり しゃべれ！
オレは 水遁のスキルは ないんじゃ～!!
You're irritating me.
Just speak clearly!
I don't have skill for
Water Style Jutsu!
えぇ～っ!!
What?!
Oh my god! Oh my god!
oh my god oh my god
yesterday's mistake got me discouraged, but
kinou no shippai de kojiketatte
Thank you! Thank you!
gottsuanda gottsuanda
my new clothes got splashed with some sauce, wow
onyuu no fuku ni sousu ga hanete wao
don't mind, don't mind, if I stay feeling like this I'll have a tear in my eyes
donmai donmai shizunda mama ja namida mo my eyes
I may be hungry and angry
donna ni hangurii de angurii demo
but I'll grab a bowl to eat and start dancing!
donburi kutte danshingu
We'll always be pals my brother!
orera itsumo demo nakama daro burazaa
hit me with an upwind or strong wind or a storm I'm ready so come on!
tatoe gyarufuu kyoufuu arashi ga fuitemo bacchikoi kamon
we may be apart but we'll still be under the same sky
hanaretetemo onaji sora no shita de
so smile and hang on
saa waratte funbatte
lets do it do it do it do it
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
even if morning doesn't come, yay yay
tatoe asa ga konakutatte yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
we'll still watch the dream together, yay yay
kimi to tomo ni yume wo miru ze yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
no matter what, don't ever, ever give up, yay yay
nani ga nandemo aa demo kou demo akirameru na yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
morning will always come after night, yay yay
donna yoru mo asa wa kuru ze yay yay
nanananana
Next Episode
How did it go? Find anything?
No, nothing.
I didn't find anything either.
The weather is making it hard
to track by scent.
Well, it's understandable
in this pouring rain...
Look, even the bats are
taking cover from the rain--
Wait!
What's wrong, Kiba-kun?
So that's the mystery behind
that dog whistle!
Kakashi Sensei, if that's the case,
our movements may be detected
by the enemy.
A Night of Rain
Next Time: "A Night of Rain"
お前 どうして
ガマ力さんが嫌いなんじゃ？
Why don't you like Gamariki-san?
アイツとは 初めから ウマが合わねえ。
We haven't gotten along
from the first time we met.
((コラボ忍術 教官の ガマ力さんだ。
Gamariki-san is a teacher
of Collaboration Jutsu.
(ガマ力)よろしくね ナルトちゃん！
Nice to meet you... Naruto-chan.
何すんだってばよ！
さぁ 修業開始よ！ 一心同体よ！
What's the big idea?!
All right, let's begin training!
One heart, one body!
もっと腰入れなさい！
全然 ダメよ！
ギャ～！
Use your hips!
おしおきよ～ん。
Terrible!
冗談じゃねえ！
I'll punish you!
こんなんじゃ
身が もたねえってばよ！
Cripes! This is ridiculous!
There's no way I can endure this!
アンタ 弱音吐くってわけ？
Are you giving up?
弱音とか
そういう問題じゃねえだろ！
おだまり!! コラボ忍術
なめてんじゃないわよ！
It's not about being weak
or whatever!
Quiet! You must not take
the Collaboration Jutsu lightly!
そっちこそ 少しは
まともな修業 考えろってばよ！
Then get serious and train me properly!
なによ
口ごたえすんじゃないわよ！
Don't talk back!
ハァ… お前には
まだ この修業は早いようだのう。
- Quiet! Quiet! Quiet!
- Training! Training! Training!
You're not ready for
this training yet.
(もう つきあいきれないわ！))
I can't put up with this anymore!
いい人なんじゃがのう…。
He's a really nice guy...